

# Sarah Fowler

# Petroleum Engineer National Capital District, Port Moresby

jerry.macapagal+sarahf@ubidy.com

+675 943 2121

### **Summary**

Experienced Petroleum Engineer with expertise in drilling operations. Resourceful professional with a strong attention to detail, excellent communication skills, and an analytical nature. Quality-focused engineer with a history of working well in fast-paced, challenging, and team-oriented environments.

#### Work experience

# **Petroleum Engineer**

Fuel Mining Pty Ltd

**Port Moresby** 

November 2019 - Present • 3 years 3 months

#### Responsibilities:

- Analyze field operations to develop improvement plans.
- Schedule and supervise equipment maintenance.
- Plan future drilling operations for new fields and expansions.
- Maintain knowledge of wide range of drilling techniques.

#### **Petroleum Engineer**

**Drill Mining Corp** 

**Port Moresby** 

February 2017 - October 2019 • 2 years 9 months

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Observed equipment and drafted reports detailing necessary changes.
- Presented findings to senior management, fielded challenging questions, and helped develop solutions.
- Gathered data and forecasted future results and failures.
- Optimized safety processes to secure personnel and equipment.

# **Petroleum Engineer**

**Fuelava Corporation** 

**Port Moresby** 

August 2013 - February 2017 • 3 years 7 months

#### Responsibilities:

- Oversaw installation and maintenance of field equipment.
- Drafted procedural documents to ensure consistent operations.
- Trained in range of techniques, including hydraulic fracking.
- · Monitored field operations and suggested improvements.

# **Education**

# **Papua New Guinea Education Institute**

Bachelor's, Petroleum Engineering

2009 - 2013

# **Affiliation**

# **PNG Engineering Society**

Member

**Port Moresby** 

2015 - Present

# Skills and competencies

#### **Advanced skills**

**Communication Skills** 

# Job preferences

Part Time, Freelance, Full Time Executive Available in 2 weeks